<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>euler on Jasblog</title>
    <link>https://jasbrg.github.io/categories/euler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in euler on Jasblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 21:08:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jasbrg.github.io/categories/euler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sum square difference</title>
      <link>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 21:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem6/</guid>
      <description>The sum of the squares of the first ten natural numbers is,
1^2 + 2^2 + ... + 10^2 = 385
The square of the sum of the first ten natural numbers is,
(1 + 2 + ... + 10)^2 = 55^2 = 3025
Hence the difference between the sum of the squares of the first ten natural numbers and the square of the sum is 3025 - 385 = 2640.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smallest multiple</title>
      <link>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 20:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem5/</guid>
      <description>2520 is the smallest number that can be divided by each of the numbers from 1 to 10 without any remainder.
What is the smallest positive number that is evenly divisible by all of the numbers from 1 to 20?
 There&amp;rsquo;s more plumbing in the form of an abstract data-type which uses a modification of Largest prime factor to find all primes of a given numbers factors. Using this information we can construct a multiset,1 here the key is a prime, and the value is its power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Largest palindrome product</title>
      <link>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem4/</guid>
      <description>A palindromic number reads the same both ways. The largest palindrome made from the product of two 2-digit numbers is 9009 = 91 × 99.
Find the largest palindrome made from the product of two 3-digit numbers.
 Loops are powerful. The Loop Macro is a very good DSL.
;;; This is trivial (defun palindrome-intp (n) (let ((s (int-to-string n))) (string-equal s (string-reverse s)))) ;;; The best way to search the problem space isn&#39;t obvious to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Largest prime factor</title>
      <link>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 10:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem3/</guid>
      <description>The prime factors of 13195 are 5, 7, 13 and 29.
What is the largest prime factor of the number 600851475143 ?
 I quickly realized a limitation of Elisp is its hacky early return from functions being based around catch and throw. It is idiomatic, but it sounds kind of ugly. We&amp;rsquo;re saved by the Loop Facility though, letting us write iterative programs, yay. It&amp;rsquo;s stateful, but whatever, the approach is sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even Fibonacci numbers</title>
      <link>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 09:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem2/</guid>
      <description>Each new term in the Fibonacci sequence is generated by adding the previous two terms. By starting with 1 and 2, the first 10 terms will be:
1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34, 55, 89, &amp;hellip;
By considering the terms in the Fibonacci sequence whose values do not exceed four million, find the sum of the even-valued terms.
 This one is still straight-forward, I&amp;rsquo;m thankful for the parallel assignment macro from cl, saves from requiring a temporary variable reducing the complexity of the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiples of 3 and 5</title>
      <link>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 08:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasbrg.github.io/euler/problem1/</guid>
      <description>If we list all the natural numbers below 10 that are multiples of 3 or 5, we get 3, 5, 6 and 9. The sum of these multiples is 23.
Find the sum of all the multiples of 3 or 5 below 1000.
 The first 100 problems of Project Euler are free for publishing, solutions can be freely discussed without offending the project runners.1 The first solution is little more than a reimplementation of the problem description in your chosen language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>